<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Dave's 2020 Vision</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/" type="text/html"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/atom.xml" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2020-01-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 1: w/c 2020-01-06</title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Although this month is mostly supposed to be about marketing, it helps
if you have something worth talking about. There were a few little problems
that I wanted to fix and I got through many of those during this week.</p>

<p>Until now, the data on the site went back to 1837 (the start of Queen
Victoria's reign). I thought it would be a good marketing hook to
have 200 years of data and, conveniently, George V came to the throne
in January 1820, so I've ensured that the data is correct back to the
start of his reign. I was also annoyed by a few bugs in the list of
positions on the individual person pages - so I spent have a day fixing
all of those.</p>

<p>I got off to a fairly slow start on the marketing front. I spent some
time building a list of people who write about the royal family for
newspapers and magazines. I then emailed those people, telling them about
the site in the hope that they might be interested in writing about it.
So far, that hasn't been successful. I've only had a single reply - and that
was just to thank me for my email. This convinced me that I needed a
<abbr title="Customer Relationship Manager">CRM</abbr> system to manage my
contacts with people like this - so I've signed up with
<a href="https://capsulecrm.com/">Capsule</a>.</p>

<p>I used to blog semi-regularly on the Line of Succession site, but that had
largely fallen away over the last year. I've set myself a task to write a
new blog post for the site every week in the month. I wrote one this week
about <a href="https://blog.lineofsuccession.co.uk/2020/01/end-of-the-line/">the people who are at the end of the line of succession</a>.
I promoted this post on both <a href="https://twitter.com/linesuccession">Twitter</a>
and <a href="https://facebook.com/linesuccession">Facebook</a>.</p>

<p>Oh, and talking about social media, the line of succession accounts are
usually quite quiet, but as I've been working on the site full time I've made
several more posts on these accounts. And the news about the Duke and Duchess
of Sussex gave me more excuses to post.</p>

<p><abbr title="Search Engine Optimisation">SEO</abbr> is an important part of
marketing. Some months ago, I signed up to <a href="https://semrush.com">SEMrush</a> so
they could periodically audit the site for basic on-page SEO errors. This week
I took a close look at their most recent report and created a couple of tasks
to look at next week.</p>

<p>Oh, and I started reading Seth Godin's book
<em><a href="https://amzn.to/2uRS90H">This is Marketing</a></em>.</p>

<p>If you're interested in following what I'm doing more closely, my
<a href="https://trello.com/b/WWetD28I/01-line-of-succession">Trello board</a> is public.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Cross &lt;dave+feed@davecross.co.uk</name>
    </author>
    <published>2020-01-06T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/#week-1-wc-2020-01-06</id>
  </entry>
</feed>
