<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Dave's 2020 Vision</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/" type="text/html"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/feed.atom" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/feed.atom</id>
  <updated>2020-02-05T15:31:24Z</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>January - Line of Succession</title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I'm starting by doing some work on a site called <a href="https://lineofsuccession.co.uk/">Line of Succession</a>.
This is a site that has existed for some time - you may have seen the video of me
<a href="https://blog.lineofsuccession.co.uk/talk/">giving a talk about it</a> to the London Perl Mongers.</p>

<p>The decision to go with an existing site for the first month was deliberate.
One of the ideas behind this whole project is that I get to learn new skills
and by choosing Line of Succession for the first month, I don't have an
excuse to spend the whole month working on technical stuff and ignoring
the other parts of the project. I'm forced to spend most of my time
working outside of my comfort zone. In this case, the thing that the
site really needs is marketing. And I know almost nothing about
marketing. So what have I been doing?</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Cross &lt;dave+feed@davecross.co.uk</name>
    </author>
    <published>2020-01-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/#january-line-of-succession</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 1: w/c 2020-01-06</title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Although this month is mostly supposed to be about marketing, it helps
if you have something worth talking about. There were a few little problems
that I wanted to fix and I got through many of those during this week.</p>

<p>Until now, the data on the site went back to 1837 (the start of Queen
Victoria's reign). I thought it would be a good marketing hook to
have 200 years of data and, conveniently, George IV came to the throne
in January 1820, so I've ensured that the data is correct back to the
start of his reign. I was also annoyed by a few bugs in the list of
positions on the individual person pages - so I spent half a day fixing
all of those.</p>

<p>I got off to a fairly slow start on the marketing front. I spent some
time building a list of people who write about the royal family for
newspapers and magazines. I then emailed those people, telling them about
the site in the hope that they might be interested in writing about it.
So far, that hasn't been successful. I've only had a single reply - and that
was just to thank me for my email. This convinced me that I needed a
<abbr title="Customer Relationship Manager">CRM</abbr> system to manage my
contacts with people like this - so I've signed up with
<a href="https://capsulecrm.com/">Capsule</a>.</p>

<p>I used to blog semi-regularly on the Line of Succession site, but that had
largely fallen away over the last year. I've set myself a task to write a
new blog post for the site every week in the month. I wrote one this week
about <a href="https://blog.lineofsuccession.co.uk/2020/01/end-of-the-line/">the people who are at the end of the line of succession</a>.
I promoted this post on both <a href="https://twitter.com/linesuccession">Twitter</a>
and <a href="https://facebook.com/linesuccession">Facebook</a>.</p>

<p>Oh, and talking about social media, the line of succession accounts are
usually quite quiet, but as I've been working on the site full time I've made
several more posts on these accounts. And the news about the Duke and Duchess
of Sussex gave me more excuses to post.</p>

<p><abbr title="Search Engine Optimisation">SEO</abbr> is an important part of
marketing. Some months ago, I signed up to <a href="https://semrush.com">SEMrush</a> so
they could periodically audit the site for basic on-page SEO errors. This week
I took a close look at their most recent report and created a couple of tasks
to look at next week.</p>

<p>Oh, and I started reading Seth Godin's book
<em><a href="https://amzn.to/2uRS90H">This is Marketing</a></em>.</p>

<p>If you're interested in following what I'm doing more closely, my
<a href="https://trello.com/b/WWetD28I/01-line-of-succession">Trello board</a> is public.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Cross &lt;dave+feed@davecross.co.uk</name>
    </author>
    <published>2020-01-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/#week-1-wc-2020-01-06</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 2: w/c 2020-01-13</title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The second week of the project had far less technical stuff in it as I
concentrated more on marketing. I still found time for a few technical
fixes though.  I found and fixed a bug where the list of blog posts was
only appearing on the front page. And I did a couple of technical SEO
fixes - setting caching headers on CSS files and adding some meta
descriptions that were missing from blog pages. As I'm only using the
free tier of <a href="https://semrush.com">SEMrush</a>, I'll have to wait a couple
of weeks before their next audit reveals how well those fixes has
worked.</p>

<p>I've been blogging on <a href="https://blog.lineofsuccession.co.uk">the site</a>
for a while and this week I added
<a href="https://blog.lineofsuccession.co.uk/2020/01/end-of-the-line-part-2/">another blog post</a>
following up on last week's exploration of people at the end of the
line of succession. I also set up a
<a href="https://medium.com/line-of-succession">Medium Publication</a> where I've
republished the older blog posts. I don't know how many people search
Medium for stories about the British Royal Family, but those who do will
now stand a chance of finding my articles. Oh, and I've signed up
for the Medium Partner Program so I can be paid if people read my posts
there.</p>

<p>An important part of marketing is to understand who your target audience.
I spend some time thinking about this and by monitoring the likes I'm
getting on my
<a href="https://www.facebook.com/linesuccession/">Facebook page</a> I've worked out
that the people most interested in my site seem to be middle-aged
American housewives (I was honestly aiming at British historians, but I
guess you take what you can). Some of the week was spend pondering
how I could extract money from this audience. Would they buy some kind
of merchandise? This is a question I'll return to this week.</p>

<p>But I do think that a book could be a good idea. I spend some time
considering what that might look like. Eventually, I decided it should
be a coffee-table book with lots of photos. It could contain short
biographies of all people who have appeared in the top twenty of the
line of succession over the last two hundred years, together with
a few essays related to the line of succession. I won't have time to
write it before the end of the month, but it's a possible project for
the future. Slightly macarbrely, the best time to promote a book like
this might be when the Queen dies.</p>

<p>I see that my first progress report was
<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/perl/comments/eqfdpn/2020_vision_of_dave_cross_line_of_succession/">posted to Reddit</a>
over the weekend. I answered a few questions there and I hope the
discussion was interesting.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Cross &lt;dave+feed@davecross.co.uk</name>
    </author>
    <published>2020-01-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/#week-2-wc-2020-01-13</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 3: w/c 2020-01-20</title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Week three was another week with very little technical work, as I
concentrated on marketing. But the
<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/perl/comments/eqfdpn/2020_vision_of_dave_cross_line_of_succession/">Reddit discussion</a>
I mentioned last week included the suggestion that I should credit the photos
that I'm using on the site. That made a lot of sense to me so I spent a
few hours checking the correct attributions and ensuring they appeared
correctly under the photos. I glad I did that, but I'm not entirely happy
with how it looks on the page. If I have some time to spare, I might try
to hide the information unless a user hovers over the photo.</p>

<p>I'm trying to stop myself reaching for Wordpress whenever I want to set up
a new site, so this site is just a static site hosted on Github Pages. That's
all very well, but I slightly miss all the stuff that Wordpress gives you for
free. For example, there was no web feed for these updates until I hacked one
together last week. And it still doesn't have the autodiscovery tags in the
HTML headers. Maybe I'll add them at some point.</p>

<p>The biggest piece of marketing I did was to create
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J51hKn74eyA&amp;t=">a video</a>
that talks people through all of the various things that you can do on the
site. But I havent done a very good job of promoting it. A week later, it's
had twenty-three views.</p>

<p>A few years ago I set up a Mailchimp account. I registered for the free
level and I mostly used it for the <a href="https://perlhacks.com/">Perl Hacks</a>
mailing list that I've been ignoring for far too long. But the free level
allowed you to have as many mailing lists as you wanted as long as your
total number of subscribers was fewer than (I think) 2,000. And I had set
up a few more mailing lists for other projects I had dabbled with. Last
week I revisited that account as I wanted to create
<a href="http://eepurl.com/gQUco5">a new list for Line of Succession</a>. But I found
that the account had been locked because the pricing plans had changed and
the free level could now only use a single mailing list (or "audience", as
they now describe them). So I've subscribed to a paid plan. And I've added
a sign-up form to the web site. Most of the marketing material I've read
agrees that getting a long list of email addresses should be one of your
prime targets - so I'm trying to do that now.</p>

<p>I did one afternoon of heavy promotion. I emailed a genealogy mailing list
about the site. That got it mentioned in a newsletter and brought about
five hundred visitors to the site. I tweeted to a number of well-known
TV historians - but got no response at all. And I emailed the owners of
a large number of royalty-focussed blogs asking them if they would be
interested in mentioning the site to their readers. I've had no response
from any of them either. I guess I need to send a follow-up email this
week. One thing I'm learning is that marketing means you need to be a lot
more persistent than I'm naturally comfortable with.</p>

<p>Oh, and one other little technical thing. I ran a
<a href="https://developers.google.com/web/tools/lighthouse">Google Lighthouse</a>
report on the site and it told me that I was using an older version of
jQuery that had a couple of vulnerabilities (version 3.2.1, if you're
interested). I've now upgraded to the most recent version - 3.4.1.</p>

<p>This week is, in theory, all about merchandise. I think the best way to
actually make some money from the site is to sell stuff to people.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Cross &lt;dave+feed@davecross.co.uk</name>
    </author>
    <published>2020-01-27T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/#week-3-wc-2020-01-20</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 4: w/c 2020-01-27</title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The final week on this project was slightly strange. To be honest, I felt
a bit down. I'm not really sure what I wanted to get out of this month (and
see  the retrospective below for more about that) but I had this vague
disappointment because I hadn't set the world on fire. But, of course, you
can't expect to do that in a month. This mild despondency made it very
tempting to retreat back into my comfortable world of coding and just spend
the week writing improvements to the site, but I forced myself not to do
that and to carry on promoting the site.</p>

<p>I mentioned that in the previous week, I had emailed some people who wrote
blogs about the royal family. I got no response from any of those people so
I sent a follow-up email offering to write a guest blog post for them. This
was way outside of my comfort zone as I couldn't help thinking about the
spammers who email me, offering me various services and then following up
a week later with "did you get my message?" I really didn't want to come
across like that, so I spend considerable time working on the best way to
phrase the email. I still got no responses.</p>

<p>I also found a few history forums and posted about my site on those. The only
response I got there was a rather snippy reply saying that they didn't
approve of self-promotion. Their site, their rules, I guess.</p>

<p>Early in the week, I posted a few items to the
<a href="https://www.facebook.com/linesuccession/">Facebook page</a> for the site and
then decided it would be worth spending a bit of money on a Facebook ad. I've
done this a few times before and I'd expect to get a couple of hundred clicks
and maybe thirty new likes on the page. But something was different this time.
Over the five days the ad was running, I got hundreds of clicks and the page
likes went from 126 to over 550. I'm not sure why this ad was so successful
(and there's another item for the retrospective) but I hope to be able to
repeat this success in the future.</p>

<p>But at the end of my last report, I said that the week was supposed to be all
about merchandise. What's the point of getting people to the page if there's
no way to extract money from them? I did spend some time thinking seriously
about this question. I was trying to work out what kind of merchandise my
users would buy. Would they want the line of succession printed on a t-shirt
(does anyone want that?) Or, perhaps, on a mug? I've previously mentioned the
idea of a book. But I didn't have enough time to write a book.</p>

<p>Then on Thursday I had an idea. The line of succession would look nice on
a poster. I found a company who make print-on-demand posters on various
sizes, on different types of paper and in various kinds of frame. And they
have an API that you can use to place an order. If I had more time (and I
might revisit this idea later on) then I would offer the chance to buy a poster
of the line of succession on any date. I'd then generate an image of that list
and use the API to get it made and sent to the customer.</p>

<p>In the end, I did put a <a href="https://linesuccession.co.uk/shop">shop page</a> on
the site, but it was only a "coming soon page" with a mocked-up book cover
along with an invitation to sign up to the mailing list.</p>

<p>I did make one tiny tweak to the site's code. Over the weekend a friend on
LinkedIn suggested that it would be nice if instead of giving a baby's age as
"0", I could give the age in months. And that turned out to be really easy
to do.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Cross &lt;dave+feed@davecross.co.uk</name>
    </author>
    <published>2020-02-03T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/#week-4-wc-2020-01-27</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>January Retrospective</title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>So what have I learned from my month working on this project? What went well?
What went less well?</p>

<p>I guess the biggest lesson is this. <strong>Marketing is hard.</strong> Or maybe it's
"I'm not particularly good at marketing".</p>

<p>Actually, that's a bit glib. Really, the biggest takeaway I have from the
month is the importance of having a plan. I spent a lot of the month either
improving the site or trying to drive people to the site when that rather
ignored the important question which is - how am I going to make money from
the site. I managed to (slightly) increase the amount of traffic to the site,
but I didn't make a single penny from all of those visitors because I didn't
have any way to take money from visitors (well, I had Google Ads, but they
generate approximately zero income).</p>

<p>So you need to have a plan. And the plan needs to look like this:</p>

<ul>
<li>Decide how you're going to make money from the site</li>
<li>Do that</li>
</ul>

<p>Just having a vague plan to "grow the audience" won't cut it. You need to
know exactly how you are going to make money and then everything you do needs
to be focussed on making that happen.</p>

<p>If I had had a better plan at the start of the month then I would have
realised the importance of merchandise on a site like this. I spend a lot of
the month thinking "oh, I should probably sell some merchandise" but putting
off actually doing that because... well, probably because it felt too hard.</p>

<p>And that's another theme from the month. A lot of this stuff is hard. It's
going to push me outside of my comfort zone. And you can't cherry-pick the
easy (i.e. programming tasks) and leave the uncomfortable stuff for later.
You need a plan and that plan needs to be executed in a sensible order.</p>

<p>So, moving forward, all of these mini-projects will need a plan. And the plan
needs to answer questions like this:</p>

<ul>
<li>How are you going to make money out of this project?</li>
<li>Who is going to use this project?</li>
<li>What are they happy to spend money on?</li>
<li>How are you going to get people like your target audience to visit the site?</li>
<li>How will you get them to spend money?</li>
</ul>

<p>Then the answers to these questions need to be used to set concrete goals for
the month. Goals that meet the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SMART_criteria">SMART</a> criteria. Goals that
are Specific, Measurable, Achievable, Realistic and Time-related. It's only
when you know what you're trying to achieve that it makes sense to start
working on it. So from now on, the introductions to my monthly projects will
include the goals for the month (which, I guess, means that the introduction
to February's project will need to wait for a few hours!)</p>

<p>Oh, and one other thing. Remember I said I had no idea why the last week's
Facebook ad worked so much better than earlier ones. That's a terrible
situation to be in. I need to be better at measuring this stuff. I need to be
able to answer questions like that. Among other things, I need to get into
A/B testing to find out what works best.</p>

<p>To summarise, I'm happy that I managed to raise the profile of the Line of
Succession site. I'm not happy that I made no money out of it. And I've
learned valuable lessons that will feed into the rest of the experiment.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Cross &lt;dave+feed@davecross.co.uk</name>
    </author>
    <published>2020-02-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/#january-retrospective</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>February - Lystyng</title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>In February, I'm going to be working on a project which is currently called
<a href="https//lystyng.com/">Lystyng</a> (but that name might not last the month).
Like Line of Succession, this is an idea that I've had knocking around for a
while and there's even some code that basically does what I what (but it's
currently in pieces as I hacked at it rather a lot last summer and didn't
put it back together when I was finished).</p>

<p>It's a pretty simple concept - it's a social media site for creating and
sharing lists.</p>

<p>You'll be able to create lists, mark them as public or private and then
share them (the public ones, of course) on other social media services.</p>

<p>I originally had a general-purpose list-sharing site in mind. But I've
decided to start by restricting it to a particular use case. I want to aim the
service at people who want to share lists of their favourite films. I think
that with a bit of magic borrowed from
<a href="https://www.themoviedb.org/">The Movie DB</a>'s API I can make the site look
pretty good by splashing film posters and stuff like that all over the page.</p>

<p>I have a few more ideas, but they'll appear (or not) during the month.</p>

<p>In my January retrospective I said I needed a clear idea of how to monetise
this projects before starting them. In this case, I do. It's a two-pronged
approach:</p>

<ul>
<li>Users pay for premium services (like lists with more than ten items)</li>
<li>Amazon affiliate links</li>
</ul>

<p>And what are my specific goals for the month?</p>

<ol>
<li>The MVP is live. Where the MVP looks like this:
<ul>
<li>Users can sign up, log in and create lists</li>
<li>Social login is supported (Facebook, Google and Twitter)</li>
<li>Users can edit and delete lists</li>
<li>Users can share lists</li>
<li>List items are enhanced with data from TMDB</li>
<li>The site is fully functional on smartphones (mobile apps will follow)</li>
</ul></li>
<li>The service has an active Facebook page and <a href="https://twitter.com/lystyng">Twitter account</a></li>
<li>I have promoted the service to a dozen student film societies</li>
<li>I have promoted the service to half a dozen film magazines</li>
</ol>

<p>And for the first week, I want to:</p>

<ol>
<li>Get the Facebook page and Twitter account up</li>
<li>Get the code back working again (without social login or TMDB cleverness)</li>
</ol>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Cross &lt;dave+feed@davecross.co.uk</name>
    </author>
    <published>2020-02-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/#february-lystyng</id>
  </entry>
</feed>
