<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Dave's 2020 Vision</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/" type="text/html"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/feed.atom" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/feed.atom</id>
  <updated>2020-01-28T10:51:51Z</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 1: w/c 2020-01-06</title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Although this month is mostly supposed to be about marketing, it helps
if you have something worth talking about. There were a few little problems
that I wanted to fix and I got through many of those during this week.</p>

<p>Until now, the data on the site went back to 1837 (the start of Queen
Victoria's reign). I thought it would be a good marketing hook to
have 200 years of data and, conveniently, George IV came to the throne
in January 1820, so I've ensured that the data is correct back to the
start of his reign. I was also annoyed by a few bugs in the list of
positions on the individual person pages - so I spent half a day fixing
all of those.</p>

<p>I got off to a fairly slow start on the marketing front. I spent some
time building a list of people who write about the royal family for
newspapers and magazines. I then emailed those people, telling them about
the site in the hope that they might be interested in writing about it.
So far, that hasn't been successful. I've only had a single reply - and that
was just to thank me for my email. This convinced me that I needed a
<abbr title="Customer Relationship Manager">CRM</abbr> system to manage my
contacts with people like this - so I've signed up with
<a href="https://capsulecrm.com/">Capsule</a>.</p>

<p>I used to blog semi-regularly on the Line of Succession site, but that had
largely fallen away over the last year. I've set myself a task to write a
new blog post for the site every week in the month. I wrote one this week
about <a href="https://blog.lineofsuccession.co.uk/2020/01/end-of-the-line/">the people who are at the end of the line of succession</a>.
I promoted this post on both <a href="https://twitter.com/linesuccession">Twitter</a>
and <a href="https://facebook.com/linesuccession">Facebook</a>.</p>

<p>Oh, and talking about social media, the line of succession accounts are
usually quite quiet, but as I've been working on the site full time I've made
several more posts on these accounts. And the news about the Duke and Duchess
of Sussex gave me more excuses to post.</p>

<p><abbr title="Search Engine Optimisation">SEO</abbr> is an important part of
marketing. Some months ago, I signed up to <a href="https://semrush.com">SEMrush</a> so
they could periodically audit the site for basic on-page SEO errors. This week
I took a close look at their most recent report and created a couple of tasks
to look at next week.</p>

<p>Oh, and I started reading Seth Godin's book
<em><a href="https://amzn.to/2uRS90H">This is Marketing</a></em>.</p>

<p>If you're interested in following what I'm doing more closely, my
<a href="https://trello.com/b/WWetD28I/01-line-of-succession">Trello board</a> is public.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Cross &lt;dave+feed@davecross.co.uk</name>
    </author>
    <published>2020-01-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/#week-1-wc-2020-01-06</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 2: w/c 2020-01-13</title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The second week of the project had far less technical stuff in it as I
concentrated more on marketing. I still found time for a few technical
fixes though.  I found and fixed a bug where the list of blog posts was
only appearing on the front page. And I did a couple of technical SEO
fixes - setting caching headers on CSS files and adding some meta
descriptions that were missing from blog pages. As I'm only using the
free tier of <a href="https://semrush.com">SEMrush</a>, I'll have to wait a couple
of weeks before their next audit reveals how well those fixes has
worked.</p>

<p>I've been blogging on <a href="https://blog.lineofsuccession.co.uk">the site</a>
for a while and this week I added
<a href="https://blog.lineofsuccession.co.uk/2020/01/end-of-the-line-part-2/">another blog post</a>
following up on last week's exploration of people at the end of the
line of succession. I also set up a
<a href="https://medium.com/line-of-succession">Medium Publication</a> where I've
republished the older blog posts. I don't know how many people search
Medium for stories about the British Royal Family, but those who do will
now stand a chance of finding my articles. Oh, and I've signed up
for the Medium Partner Program so I can be paid if people read my posts
there.</p>

<p>An important part of marketing is to understand who your target audience.
I spend some time thinking about this and by monitoring the likes I'm
getting on my
<a href="https://www.facebook.com/linesuccession/">Facebook page</a> I've worked out
that the people most interested in my site seem to be middle-aged
American housewives (I was honestly aiming at British historians, but I
guess you take what you can). Some of the week was spend pondering
how I could extract money from this audience. Would they buy some kind
of merchandise? This is a question I'll return to this week.</p>

<p>But I do think that a book could be a good idea. I spend some time
considering what that might look like. Eventually, I decided it should
be a coffee-table book with lots of photos. It could contain short
biographies of all people who have appeared in the top twenty of the
line of succession over the last two hundred years, together with
a few essays related to the line of succession. I won't have time to
write it before the end of the month, but it's a possible project for
the future. Slightly macarbrely, the best time to promote a book like
this might be when the Queen dies.</p>

<p>I see that my first progress report was
<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/perl/comments/eqfdpn/2020_vision_of_dave_cross_line_of_succession/">posted to Reddit</a>
over the weekend. I answered a few questions there and I hope the
discussion was interesting.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Cross &lt;dave+feed@davecross.co.uk</name>
    </author>
    <published>2020-01-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/#week-2-wc-2020-01-13</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 3: w/c 2020-01-20</title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Week three was another week with very little technical work, as I
concentrated on marketing. But the
<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/perl/comments/eqfdpn/2020_vision_of_dave_cross_line_of_succession/">Reddit discussion</a>
I mentioned last week included the suggestion that I should credit the photos
that I'm using on the site. That made a lot of sense to me so I spend a
few hours checking the correct attribution and ensuring they appeared
correctly under the photos. I glad I did that, but I'm not entirely happy
with how it looks on the page. If I have some time to spare, I might try
to hide the information unless a user hovers over the photo.</p>

<p>I'm trying to stop myself reaching for Wordpress whenever I want to set up
a new site, so this site is just a static site hosted on Github Pages. That's
all very well, but slightly miss all the stuff that Wordpress gives you for
free. For example, there was no web feed for this updates until I hacked one
together last week. And it still doesn't have the autodiscovery tags in the
HTML headers. Maybe I'll add them at some point.</p>

<p>The biggest piece of marketing I did was to create
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J51hKn74eyA&amp;t=">a video</a>
that talks people through all of the various things that you can do on the
site. But I havent done a very good job of promoting it. A week later, it's
had twenty-three views.</p>

<p>A few years ago I set up a Mailchimp account. I registered for the free
level and I mostly used it for the <a href="https://perlhacks.com/">Perl Hacks</a>
mailing list that I've been ignoring for far too long. But the free level
allowed you to have as many mailing lists as you wanted as long as your
total number of subscribers was fewer than (I think) 2,000. And I had set
up a few more mailing lists for other projects I had dabbled with. Last
week I revisited that account as I wanted to create a new list for Line
of Succession. But I found that the account had been locked because the
pricing plans had changed and the free level could only use a single
mailing list (or "audience", as they now describe them). So I've subscribed
to a paid plan. And I've added a sign-up to the web site. Most of the
marketing material I've read agrees that getting a long list of email
addresses should be one of your prime targets - so I'm trying to do that
now.</p>

<p>I did one afternoon of heavy promotion. I emailed a genealogy mailing list
about the site. That got it mentioned in a newsletter and brought about
five hundred visitors to the site. I tweeted to a number of well-known
TV historians - but got no response at all. And I emailed the owners of
a large number of royalty-focussed blogs asking them if they would be
interested in mentioning the site to their readers. I've had no response
from any of them either. I guess I need to send a follow-up email this
week. One thing I'm learning is that marketing means you need to be a lot
more persistent than I'm naturally comfortable with.</p>

<p>Oh, and one other little technical thing. I ran a
<a href="https://developers.google.com/web/tools/lighthouse">Google Lighthouse</a>
report on the site and it told me that I was using an older version of
jQuery that had a couple of vulnerabilities (version 3.2.1, if you're
interested). I've now upgraded to the most recent version - 3.4.1.</p>

<p>This week is, in theory, all about merchandise. I think the best way to
actually make some money from the site is to sell stuff to people.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Cross &lt;dave+feed@davecross.co.uk</name>
    </author>
    <published>2020-01-27T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://davecross.co.uk/2020-vision/#week-3-wc-2020-01-20</id>
  </entry>
</feed>
